Finding Aid for the Adeline Levine Love Canal Collection, 1893-1995 (bulk 1978-1995)
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
- Newspaper Clippings, XII.
  - September 1-9, 1981 (Box-folder 41.15)
  - September 10-30, 1981 (Box-folder 41.16)
  - October 1-14, 1981 (Box-folder 41.17)
  - October 15-31, 1981 (Box-folder 41.18)
  - November 1-19, 1981 (Box-folder 41.19)
  - November 20-30, 1981 (Box-folder 41.20)
  - December 1981 (Box-folder 41.21)
  - January 1982 (Box-folder 41.22)
  - February 1-16, 1982 (Box-folder 41.23)
  - February 17-28, 1982 (Box-folder 41.24)
  - March 1-17, 1982 (Box-folder 41.25)
  - March 18-31, 1982 (Box-folder 41.26)
  - April 1-14, 1982 (Box-folder 42.1)
  - April 15-30, 1982 (Box-folder 42.2)
  - May 1-14, 1982 (Box-folder 42.3)
  - May 15-31, 1982 (Box-folder 42.4)
  - June 1-17, 1982 (Box-folder 42.5)
  - June 18-30, 1982 (Box-folder 42.6)
  - July 1-13, 1982 (Box-folder 42.7)
  - July 14-15, 1982 (Box-folder 42.8)
  - July 16-31, 1982 (Box-folder 42.9)
  - August 1-14, 1982 (Box-folder 42.10)
  - August 15-31, 1982 (Box-folder 42.11)
  - September 1-5, 1982 (Box-folder 42.12)
  - September 6-30, 1982 (Box-folder 42.13)
  - October 1-14, 1982 (Box-folder 42.14)
  - October 15-31, 1982 (Box-folder 42.15)
  - November 1-20, 1982 (Box-folder 42.16)
  - November 21-30, 1982 (Box-folder 42.17)
  - December 1-4, 1982 (Box-folder 42.18)
  - December 5-8, 1982 (Box-folder 42.19)
  - December 9-11, 1982 (Box-folder 42.20)
  - December 12-15, 1982 (Box-folder 42.21)
  - December 16-18, 1982 (Box-folder 42.22)
  - December 20-22, 1982 (Box-folder 42.23)
  - December 23-26, 1982 (Box-folder 42.24)
  - December 27-31, 1982 (Box-folder 42.25)
  - January 1-6, 1983 (Box-folder 43.1)
  - January 7-9, 1983 (Box-folder 43.2)
  - January 10-12, 1983 (Box-folder 43.3)
  - January 13-23, 1983 (Box-folder 43.4)
  - January 24-31, 1983 (Box-folder 43.5)
  - February 1-9, 1983 (Box-folder 43.6)
  - February 10-13, 1983 (Box-folder 43.7)
  - February 14-17, 1983 (Box-folder 43.8)
  - February 18-20, 1983 (Box-folder 43.9)
  - February 21-23, 1983 (Box-folder 43.10)
  - February 24-25, 1983 (Box-folder 43.11)
  - February 26-28, 1983 (Box-folder 43.12)
  - March l-10, 1983 (Box-folder 43.13)
  - March 11-19, 1983 (Box-folder 43.14)
  - March 20-30, 1983 (Box-folder 43.15)
  - April 1-18, 1983 (Box-folder 43.16)
  - April 17-22, 1983 (Box-folder 43.17)
  - April 22-31, 1983 (Box-folder 43.18)
  - May 1-15, 1983 (Box-folder 44.1)
  - May 26-32, 1983 (Box-folder 44.2)
  - June 1-8, 1983 (Box-folder 44.3)
  - June 9-21, 1983 (Box-folder 44.4)
  - June 22-30, 1983 (Box-folder 44.5)
  - July 1-10, 1983 (Box-folder 44.6)
  - July 11-31, 1983 (Box-folder 44.7)
  - August 2-18, 1983 (Box-folder 44.8)
  - August 20-31, 1983 (Box-folder 44.9)
  - September 1983 (Box-folder 44.10)
  - October 1-14, 1983 (Box-folder 44.11)
  - October 16-32, 1983 (Box-folder 44.12)
  - November 1983 (Box-folder 44.13)
  - December 1983 (Box-folder 44.14)
  - January 1-18, 1984 (Box-folder 44.15)
  - January 17-31, 1984 (Box-folder 44.16)
  - February 1984 (Box-folder 44.17)
  - March 1984 (Box-folder 44.18)
  - April 1984 (Box-folder 44.19)
  - May 1984 (Box-folder 44.20)
  - June 1984 (Box-folder 44.21)
  - July 1-20, 1984 (Box-folder 45.1)
  - July 21-31, 1984 (Box-folder 45.2)
  - August 1984 (Box-folder 45.3)
  - September 1984 (Box-folder 45.4)
  - October 1984 (Box-folder 45.5)
  - November 1-18, 1984 (Box-folder 45.6)
  - November 19-30, 1984 (Box-folder 45.7)
  - December 1984 (Box-folder 45.8)
  - January 1985 (Box-folder 45.9)
  - February 1985 (Box-folder 45.10)
  - March 1985 (Box-folder 45.11)
  - May 1985 (Box-folder 45.13)
  - June 1985 (Box-folder 45.14)
  - July 1985 (Box-folder 45.15)
  - August 1985 (Box-folder 45.16)
  - September 1985 (Box-folder 45.17)
  - October 1988 (Box-folder 45.18)
  - November-December 1985 (Box-folder 45.19)
  - January-February 1986 (Box-folder 45.20)
  - March-April 1986 (Box-folder 45.21)
  - May-June 1986 (Box-folder 45.22)
  - July-August 1986 (Box-folder 45.23)
  - September-October 1986 (Box-folder 45.24)
  - November-December 1986 (Box-folder 45.25)
  - January-February 1987 (Box-folder 45.26)
  - March-April 1987 (Box-folder 45.27)
  - May-June 1987 (Box-folder 45.28)
  - July-August 1987 (Box-folder 46.1)
  - September 1987 (Box-folder 46.2)
  - October 1987 (Box-folder 46.3)
  - November 1987 (Box-folder 46.4)
  - December 1987 (Box-folder 46.5)
  - January 1988 (Box-folder 46.6)
  - February-March 1988 (Box-folder 46.7)
  - April-May 1988 (Box-folder 46.8)
  - June-July 1988 (Box-folder 46.9)
  - August 1988 (Box-folder 46.10)
  - September-October 1988 (Box-folder 46.11)
  - November-December 1988 (Box-folder 46.12)
  - January-February 1989 (Box-folder 46.13)
  - March-May 1989 (Box-folder 46.14)
  - June-August 1989 (Box-folder 46.15)
  - September-December 1989 (Box-folder 46.16)
  - January-April 1990 (Box-folder 46.17)
  - May-July 1990 (Box-folder 46.18)
  - August-September 1990 (Box-folder 46.19)
  - October 1990 (Box-folder 46.20)
  - November-December 1990 (Box-folder 46.21)
  - January-February 1991 (Box-folder 46.22)
  - March-April 1991 (Box-folder 46.23)
  - May 1991 (Box-folder 46.24)
  - June-August 1991 (Box-folder 46.25)
  - September-December 1991 (Box-folder 46.26)
  - January-March 1992 (Box-folder 46.27)
  - April-July, December 1992 (Box-folder 46.28)
  - 1993 (Box-folder 46.29)
  - 1994-1995 (Box-folder 46.30)
  - Newspaper article index, undated through 1977, January-July 1978, August 1978-February 1979 (Box 47)
  - Newspaper article index, March 1979-October 14, 1979 (Box 48)
  - Newspaper article index, October 15, 1979-June 5, 1980 (Box 49)
  - Newspaper article index, June 6, 1980-April 3, 1981 (Box 50)
  - Newspaper article index, May 1981-February 17, 1983 (Box 51)
  - Newspaper article index, February 18, 1983-August 1984 (Box 52)
  - Newspaper article index, September 1984-1990 (Box 53)
  - Newspaper article index, 1991-1995. Levine bibliographic cards (Box 54)
- Audio and Video Cassettes, XIII.
  - Lois and Debbie address psych meeting, November 16, 1978, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.1)
  - Paigen, November 26, 1978, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.2-55.4)
  - Judy Keys at seminar, December 15, 1978, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.5-55.6)
  - Seminar, January 31: 1979, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.7-55.8)
  - Speech, engineers, May 10, 1979, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.9)
  - Paigen, June 18, 1979, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.10-55.11)
  - Gibbs, Lester, Levine re health, United Way, June 25, 1979, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.12-55.13)
  - "Challenge" program, Ch. 7 - Gibbs and Pat Pino, 1979 or 1980, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.14)
  - Psychiatric Grand Rounds - Levine, "A Participant-Observer Study of Love Canal", October 3, 1980, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.15)
  - SUNYAB, community health, October 23, 1980 and November 6, 1980, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.16)
  - Nazareth College, confrontation with Doherty, March 27, 1981, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.17)
  - American University, talk to environmental law group, "Assessing Liability and Damage at Love Canal", January 28, 1982, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.18)
  - 101 class, November 11, 1982, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.19)
  - NPR, "All Things Considered", report on St. Louis, December 7, 1982, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.20)
  - Paigen, presentation to community, April 29, 1983, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.21)
  - Abrams re Love Canal land use, 1985-1988?, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.22)
  - "Love Canal: The Issues and The Controversies" slide show narration, [audio cassette] (Box-folder 55.23-55.24)
  - "Love Canal", February 17, 1982, [video cassette] (Box-folder 56.1)
  - ABC-TV, program on toxic waste, acceptable risk, March 9, 1986, [video cassette] (Box-folder 56.2)
  - "Love Canal", undated, [video cassette] (Box-folder 56.3)
  - "In Our Own Backyard: A Videotape by Lynn Corcoran", [video cassette] (Box-folder 56.4)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Gibbs, Lois Marie; Paigen, Beverly; Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Wastes (Arlington, Va.); Center for Health, Environment and Justice (Falls Church, Va.); Buffalo History Museum; State University of New York at Buffalo. University Archives
Subject Terms
Hazardous waste sites--New York (State)--Niagara Falls; Environmental health--New York (State)--Niagara Falls; Love Canal Chemical Waste Landfill (Niagara Falls, N.Y.); Hooker Chemicals & Plastics Corp
Genre Terms
Audiovisual materials; Clippings files; Field notes; Interviews; Photographs
Associated Material
Related Resources at the University Archives, The State University of New York at Buffalo
The University Archives at the State University of New York at Buffalo have the world's largest collection of Love Canal Materials. Their website for the collections
http://library.buffalo.edu/specialcollections/lovecanal
describe each collection, most have online finding aids. Also included are a glossary of names, organizations, and buildings related to Love Canal; chronologies; newspaper clipping citation database; digital image collection and related links.
22/3F/0634
Adeline Levine Love Canal Research Materials (Part I), 1953-1981 (1978-1981 bulk)
22/3F/1113
Adeline Levine Love Canal Research Materials (Part II), 1980-1991